<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How To on menziess blog</title>
    <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How To on menziess blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://menziess.github.io/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your Databricks Workflow</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/enhance/your-databricks-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 07:15:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/enhance/your-databricks-workflow/</guid>
      <description>With databricks-connect you can connect your favorite IDE to your Databricks cluster. This means that you can now lint, test, and package the code that you want to run on Databricks more easily:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Python Packages</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/create/python-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 07:15:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/create/python-packages/</guid>
      <description>Why should you care about creating packages?
 packages are easy to install (pip install demo). packages simplify development (pip install -e . installs your package and keeps it up-to-date). packages are easy to run and test (from demo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your Python-vscode Workflow</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/enhance/your-python-vscode-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 07:15:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/enhance/your-python-vscode-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This post covers my personal workflow for python projects, using Visual Studio Code along with some other tools. A good workflow saves time and allows you to focus on the problem at hand, instead of tasks that make you feel like a robot (machines are good for that).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install databricks-connect</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/install/databricks-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 07:15:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/install/databricks-connect/</guid>
      <description>Databricks-connect allows you to connect your favorite IDE to your Databricks cluster.
⟶ Visit your Databricks cluster page, and verify that your cluster supports python3, then add the following lines to the Spark Config:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Windows Subsystem for Linux</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/install/windows-subsystem-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 07:15:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/install/windows-subsystem-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re accustomed to using a unix shell as your command-line interface, you may end up being very unproductive using Windows 10.
Microsoft (in collaboration with Canonical) has made a tremendous effort into closing the gap between Linux and Windows developers by creating a kernel compatibility layer based on Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Python Code</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/test/python-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 09:39:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/test/python-code/</guid>
      <description>Writing unit tests should an integral part of delivering software for every developer. Whenever a piece of code is changed, it has the potential to break all other parts. The broken parts can even be discovered in a far later stage, having caused potential damage that is hard to restore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Code in Databricks Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/test/code-in-databricks-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:49:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/test/code-in-databricks-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>Companies hire developers to write spark applications &amp;ndash; using expensive Databricks clusters &amp;ndash; transforming and delivering business-critical data to the end user. It would be best to properly package and test your code before you run it in production on Databricks clusters, like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Virtual Environments</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/manage/virtual-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 10:00:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/manage/virtual-environments/</guid>
      <description>In this post we will take a look at using Pipenv, a dependency manager for python, to boost your python workflow. A virtual environment is an isolated environment in which dependencies for a python project are contained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Python Versions</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/manage/python-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 09:17:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/manage/python-versions/</guid>
      <description>This will be a micro-post talking about managing multiple python versions on your machine, using a tool called Pyenv. Depending on your operating system, it may be quite a hassle uninstalling and installing different python versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Blog</title>
      <link>https://menziess.github.io/howto/create/a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 23:31:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://menziess.github.io/howto/create/a-blog/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will walk you through all the steps that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to create and publish this static blog website using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>